Guide to the Henry Ernest Sigerist Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1897-(1913-1957)-1970; Series I; 12 linear feet (30 boxes)
  - General, 1947-1957
    - Schinz, Ginevra (Mrs. Hans R.), 1954-1956, undated (Box 21, Folder 772)
    - Schinz, Hans R.(*), 1947-1956 (Box 21, Folder 773)
    - Schmid, Harald E., 1953 (Box 21, Folder 774)
    - Schönbauer, L.(*), 1956 (Box 21, Folder 774)
    - Schopfer, William H., 1948-1951 (Box 21, Folder 775)
    - Schullian, Dorothy M.(*), 1948-1951 (Box 21, Folder 775)
    - Schullian, Dorothy M.(*), 1952-1956 (Box 21, Folder 776)
    - Schulthess, Henri von(*), 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 777)
    - Schultz, Adolf H.(*), 1948-1956 (Box 22, Folder 778)
      See also: box 27, folder 924 See also: box 7, folder 263-266
    - Schumacher, J., 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 778)
    - Schuman, Henry(*), 1947-1950 (Box 22, Folder 779)
      See also: box 7, folder 254 See also: box 8, folder 306 See also: box 27, folder 934
    - Schuman, Henry(*), 1951-1953 (Box 22, Folder 780)
    - Schuman, Henry(*), 1954-1956 (Box 22, Folder 781)
    - Schuman, Ida (Mrs. Henry), 1954-1956 (Box 22, Folder 782)
    - Schwabe (Benno) & Co. Verlag, 1948-1951 (Box 22, Folder 783)
    - Schwartz, L. Laszlo, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 783)
    - Schwarz, [F. A.?](*) (Box 22, Folder 784)
    - Schwarz, S. F., 1952 (Box 22, Folder 785)
    - Schwarzbock, Linn, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 785)
    - Schweingruber, Robert, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 786)
    - Schweizerische Akademie der Medizinischen Wissenschaften, 1950-1952 (Box 22, Folder 786)
    - Schweizerische Bewegung für den Frieden, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 787)
    - Schweizerische Landesbibliothek, 1948-1955 (Box 22, Folder 787)
    - Schweizerische Naturforschende Gesellschaft, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 788)
    - Schweizerische Paracelsus Gesellschaft, 1949, 1954, undated (Box 22, Folder 788)
    - Schwetz, Jacques, 1948-1949 (Box 22, Folder 789)
    - Seemann, Erich(*), 1953-1956 (Box 22, Folder 789)
    - Selver, Henry(*), 1950 (Box 22, Folder 790)
    - Sen, Sri Satiranjan(*), 1953 (Box 22, Folder 791)
    - Seymer, Lucy (Mrs. Vivian), 1949-1955 (Box 22, Folder 791)
    - Sforza, G., 1949, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 792)
    - Shah, M. H., 1949 (Box 22, Folder 792)
    - Shapiro, Gerald, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 793)
    - Sheps, Cecil G.(*), 1948 (Box 22, Folder 793)
    - Sheps, Cecil G.(*), 1949-1956 (Box 22, Folder 794)
    - Sheps, Mindel (Mrs. Cecil G.), 1947-1956 (Box 22, Folder 794)
    - Shryock, Richard H.(*), 1947-1949 (Box 22, Folder 795)
    - Shryock, Richard H.(*), 1950-1956 (Box 22, Folder 796)
    - Siemens, B. Müller (Mrs. H. W.), 1954 (Box 22, Folder 797)
    - Sigerist Society
      See: box 15, folder 557
    - Silver, George A.(*), 1947-1956 (Box 22, Folder 798)
    - Silverman, Charlotte(*), 1949-1956, undated (Box 22, Folder 799)
    - Simmons, Winifred (Mrs. Ernest J.), 1952-1953, undated (Box 22, Folder 799)
    - Singer, Charles(*), 1947-1956 (Box 22, Folder 800-803)
    - Singer, Dorothea Waley (Mrs. Charles)(*), 1948-1956, undated (Box 22, Folder 804)
    - Singh, B. H., 1947 (Box 22, Folder 804)
    - Smit, J. H. Sypkens, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 805)
    - Smith, Jessica(*), 1947-1956 (Box 22, Folder 805)
    - Snorrason, Egill(*), 1947-1952 (Box 22, Folder 806)
    - Sobotka, Harry, 1953-1956, undated (Box 22, Folder 807)
    - Socialist Medical Association, 1952-1954 (Box 22, Folder 807)
    - Sokhey, Sahib Singh, 1951-1954 (Box 22, Folder 808)
    - Sparkuhl, Alex, 1954-1956 (Box 22, Folder 809)
    - Sparkuhl, Konstantin(*), 1947-1950 (Box 22, Folder 809)
    - Sparkuhl, Konstantin(*), 1951-1956, undated (Box 23, Folder 810)
    - Sparkuhl, Mary
      See: box 22, folder 809
    - Spatz, H., 1951-1954 (Box 23, Folder 811)
    - Spector, Benjamin(*), 1948-1953 (Box 23, Folder 811)
    - Spiess, Otto, 1949-1951 (Box 23, Folder 812)
    - Spitzer, Leo, 1949, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 812)
    - Spivak, Sydney S.(*), 1947-1956 (Box 23, Folder 813)
    - Stähelin, F., 1947 (Box 23, Folder 814)
    - Staehelin-Bosshard, A., 1952 (Box 23, Folder 814)
    - Štampar, Andrija(*), 1947-1956 (Box 23, Folder 815-816)
    - Štampar, ____ (Mrs, A.), 1949 (Box 23, Folder 817)
    - Stanojević, Lazar, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 817)
    - Stanton, Madeline(*), 1949-1955 (Box 23, Folder 818)
    - Stapleton, William J., Jr., 1951-1955 (Box 23, Folder 818)
    - Stein, Gunther, 1952-1955 (Box 23, Folder 819)
    - Steinmann, Erik P., 1952, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 819)
    - Stelling-Michaud, Sven, 1952-1956 (Box 23, Folder 820)
    - Stern, Bernhard J., 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 820)
    - Stern, Lina, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 821)
    - Sternberg, F., 1949 (Box 23, Folder 821)
    - Steudel, Johannes(*), 1952-1956 (Box 23, Folder 822)
    - Steuer, Robert O.(*), 1948-1955 (Box 23, Folder 822)
    - Stevenson, Lloyd G.(*), 1949-1956 (Box 23, Folder 823)
      See also: box 27, folder 934 See also: box 7, folder 271
    - Steward, C. M., 1950, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 824)
    - Stiasny, Eva D.(*), 1954-1955 July (Box 23, Folder 824)
    - Stiasny, Eva D.(*), 1955 August-1956, undated (Box 23, Folder 825)
    - Stieve, Marie (Box 23, Folder 825)
    - Stock, ____, 1947-1952 (Box 23, Folder 826)
    - Stocker, Frederick W., 1947-1955 (Box 23, Folder 826)
    - Stokar, Hermann G., 1948 (Box 23, Folder 827)
    - Stroomann, Gerhard(*), 1953-1955 (Box 23, Folder 828)
    - Subba Reddy, D. V.
    - Sudhoff, Ernst, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 828)
    - Suggett, Allen Holman(*), 1948-1955 (Box 23, Folder 829)
    - Sung, Ta-Yen, 1947-1955 (Box 23, Folder 829)
    - Sutermeister, Hans, 1948-1955, undated (Box 23, Folder 830)
    - Swiss Legation, Washington, D. C., 1947 (Box 23, Folder 831)
    - Sze, Joan (Mrs. T. S.), 1950 (Box 23, Folder 831)
    - Sze, T. S.(*), 1949-1952 (Box 23, Folder 832)
    - Sze, T. S.(*), 1953-1956 (Box 23, Folder 833)
    - Szumowski, Wladyslaw, 1947-1950 (Box 23, Folder 833)
    - T (Box 23, Folder 834)
    - Tait, H. P.(*), 1951-1956 (Box 23, Folder 835)
    - Talbot, Nell Snow (Mrs. Bryce)(*) (Box 23, Folder 835)
    - Taniguchi, Mari(*), 1952-1955 (Box 23, Folder 836)
    - Tannenbaum, Gerald(*), 1951-1955 (Box 23, Folder 837)
    - Temkin, Lilian (Mrs. Owsei), 1956 (Box 23, Folder 837)
    - Temkin, Owsei(*), 1947-1949 (Box 23, Folder 838-839)
    - Temkin, Owsei(*), 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 840)
    - Temkin, Owsei(*), 1952-1956 (Box 23, Folder 841-842)
    - Terris, Milton, 1948-1949 (Box 24, Folder 843)
    - Thomas, Karl, 1947-1953 (Box 24, Folder 843)
    - Thoma-Wolters, Gertrud (Mrs.), 1949 (Box 24, Folder 844)
    - Thomson, Elizabeth H., 1951, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 844)
    - Thorwald, Jürgen, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 845)
    - Tiegel, Werner, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 845)
    - Tjomsland, Anna(*), 1948-1954 (Box 24, Folder 846)
    - Tjomsland, Anna(*), 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 847)
    - Tobler, Walter, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 848)
    - Tománek, Evald, 1949-1956 (Box 24, Folder 848)
    - Trent, Josiah Charles, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 849)
    - Trent, Mary (Mrs. Josiah C.), 1949 (Box 24, Folder 849)
    - Trümpy, Hans, 1952-1955 (Box 24, Folder 850)
    - Tsuda, Yasushi(*), 1951-1954 (Box 24, Folder 850)
    - U (Box 24, Folder 851)
    - Ũnver, A. Süheyl, 1949, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 852)
    - Ulich, Robert, 1948, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 852)
    - Underwood, E. Ashworth(*), 1947-1953 (Box 24, Folder 853-857)
    - Underwood, E. Ashworth(*), 1954-1956 (Box 24, Folder 858)
    - Underwood, Nancy (Mrs. E. Ashworth), 1950, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 858)
    - UNESCO, 1949-1956 (Box 24, Folder 859)
    - Union Health Center, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 859)
    - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, Berne Legation, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 860)
    - United States Foreign Service, Consulate General, Zurich, 1949, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 860)
    - Urdang, George(*), 1947-1949 (Box 24, Folder 861)
    - Urdang, George(*), 1950-1956 (Box 24, Folder 862)
    - V (Box 24, Folder 863)
    - Vaillancourt, Emile(*), 1948-1956 (Box 24, Folder 864)
    - Valentin, Bruno, 1950-1956 (Box 24, Folder 864)
    - Vasconcellos, Ivolino de, 1950-1956, undated (Box 24, Folder 865)
    - Vaughan, Janet(*), 1949-1952 (Box 24, Folder 865)
    - Veith, Ilza (Mrs. Hans)(*), 1947-1956 (Box 24, Folder 866-869)
    - Vellay-Dalsace, A. P. (Mrs. Pierre), 1947 (Box 24, Folder 870)
    - Verin, Layna(*), 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 870)
      See also: box 16, folder 596
    - Vetter, Quido, 1945-1951 (Box 24, Folder 871)
    - Viets, Henry R.(*), 1947-1951 (Box 24, Folder 871)
    - Viets, Henry R.(*), 1952-1956 (Box 24, Folder 872)
    - VOKS (U.S.S.R. Society for Cultural Relations with Foreign Countries), 1947, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 873)
    - Vollman, R. F.(*), 1952-1956 (Box 24, Folder 873)
    - Von Fischer, Hans
      See: box 11, folder 432
    - Vonwiller, Magali (Mrs. Paul), 1949 (Box 24, Folder 874)
    - Vonwiller, Paul(*), 1947-1956 (Box 24, Folder 874)
    - Wa-Web (Box 25, Folder 875)
    - Weg-Wi (Box 25, Folder 876)
    - Wo-Wy (Box 25, Folder 877)
    - Waksman, Selman A., 1952 (Box 25, Folder 878)
    - Waldkirch, Gertrud von, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 878)
    - Walker, William B., 1956 (Box 25, Folder 879)
    - Waller, Erik(*), 1949-1954 (Box 25, Folder 879)
    - Wallerstein, Robert S., 1955 (Box 25, Folder 880)
    - Walter, Emil J., 1948, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 880)
    - Warburg, Edward M. M., undated (Box 25, Folder 881)
    - Warburg, Erik, 1950, 1953, undated (Box 25, Folder 881)
    - Wardwell, W., 1952 (Box 25, Folder 882)
    - Wastl, Helene, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 882)
    - Weber, Hellmut H., 1954 (Box 25, Folder 882)
    - Weber-Marshall, Jean, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 883)
    - Webster, Emily Randall (Mrs. Jerome), 1952 (Box 25, Folder 883)
    - Webster, Jerome Pierce, 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 884)
    - Wedekind, Armin, 1947-1957, undated (Box 25, Folder 884)
    - Wegelin, Carl, 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 885)
    - Weinberger, Bernhard Wolf, 1948-1949 (Box 25, Folder 885)
    - Weinerman, E. Richard(*), 1948-1955 (Box 25, Folder 886)
    - Weinstein, Bernard, 1948-1956 (Box 25, Folder 887)
    - Weisbach, W., 1947 (Box 25, Folder 887)
    - Weisberger, Siegfried(*), 1947-1955 (Box 25, Folder 888)
    - Wellcome Historical Medical Library(*), 1950-1956 (Box 25, Folder 888)
    - Wendeborn, C., 1952 (Box 25, Folder 889)
    - Wenger, A.(*), 1951-1954 (Box 25, Folder 889)
    - Wenger, Otto M., 1956 (Box 25, Folder 890)
    - Werden and Wirken Verlag(*), 1948-1949 (Box 25, Folder 891)
    - Werman, David S., 1949-1951 (Box 25, Folder 892)
    - Wheeler, Helen(*), 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 892)
    - Wheeler, Helen(*), 1949-1954 (Box 25, Folder 893)
    - Wheelwright, Mary C., undated (Box 25, Folder 893)
    - Wicke, Berta, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 894)
    - Wickersheimer, Ernest, 1951-1955 (Box 25, Folder 894)
    - Wigmore, Ethel, 1951 (Box 25, Folder 895)
    - Wild, Margrit Stocker(*), 1948-1954 (Box 25, Folder 895)
    - Wild, Margrit Stocker(*), 1955-1956, undated (Box 25, Folder 896)
    - Wild, Rudi, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 896)
    - Wildbolz, Egon, 1948, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 897)
    - Wildbolz, M. (Mrs. Egon), 1948 (Box 25, Folder 897)
    - Williams, Huntington, 1954-1956 (Box 25, Folder 898)
    - Williams & Wilkins Company, 1948, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 898)
    - Wilson, Gwyn (Mrs. Rodman)(*), 1947-1955 (Box 25, Folder 898)
    - Winter, Ella (Mrs. Don Stewart), 1949, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 899)
    - Winterstein, O., 1954 (Box 25, Folder 899)
    - Wislocki, Florence (Mrs. George B,), 1956 (Box 25, Folder 900)
    - Wislocki, George B., 1951-1956, undated (Box 25, Folder 900)
    - Witwatersrand, University of the, 1952-1954 (Box 25, Folder 901)
    - Wolff, George, 1947-1951 (Box 25, Folder 902)
    - Wolff, Pablo Osvaldo, 1947-1955 (Box 25, Folder 902)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom(*), 1947-1952 (Box 25, Folder 903)
    - Wong, K. Chimin, 1948-1956, undated (Box 25, Folder 904)
    - World Health Organization(*), 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 905-906)
    - World Health Organization(*), 1953-1957, undated (Box 25, Folder 907)
      See also: box 10, folder 390 See also: box 11, folder 436
    - World Health Organization, Social and Occupational Health Section
    - Wortis, Joseph, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 908)
    - Wright, Robert D., 1951-1955 (Box 25, Folder 908)
    - Wunderwald, Alfred, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 908)
    - Y (Box 26, Folder 909)
    - Z (Box 26, Folder 910)
    - Zaunick, Rudolph, 1951, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 911)
    - Zekert, Otto, 1951-1954 (Box 26, Folder 911)
    - Ziegler, K. A., 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 912)
    - Zilboorg, Gregory(*), 1947-1949 (Box 26, Folder 912)
    - Zilboorg, Gregory(*), 1950-1953 June-Jul, 1954-1956 (Box 26, Folder 913-917)
    - Zurich, University of, 1947-1948 (Box 26, Folder 918)
    - Zurich, University of(*), 1949-1956 (Box 26, Folder 919-920)
    - Zurukzoglu, Stavros, 1948-1951 (Box 26, Folder 921)
    - Unidentified (given name A-L) (Box 26, Folder 922)
    - Unidentified (given name M-2) (Box 26, Folder 923)
  - Topical, 1947-1957
    - Birthday letters (A-Z), 1951 (Box 27, Folder 924)
    - Booksellers, libraries, and publishers (A-C): printed matter and routine correspondence, 1947-1957 (Box 27, Folder 925)
    - Booksellers, libraries, and publishers (D-F): printed matter and routine correspondence, 1947-1957 (Box 27, Folder 926)
    - Booksellers, libraries, and publishers (G-H); printed matter and routine correspondence, 1947-1957 (Box 27, Folder 927)
    - Booksellers, libraries, and publishers (I-P): printed matter and routine correspondence, 1947-1957 (Box 27, Folder 928)
    - Booksellers, libraries, and publishers (Q-S): printed matterand routine correspondence, 1947-1957 (Box 27, Folder 929)
    - Booksellers, libraries, and publishers (T-Wh): printed matterand routine correspondence, 1947-1957 (Box 27, Folder 930)
    - Booksellers, libraries, and publishers (Wi-Z): printed matterand routine correspondence, 1947-1957 (Box 27, Folder 931)
    - C.A.R.E.: printed matter and correspondence, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 932)
    - Casa Serena, purchase of: correspondence, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 933)
    - Farewell letters (A-Z), 1947-1948 (Box 27, Folder 934)
    - Gardening; printed matter and correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 28, Folder 935)
    - "Leipzig Schiller": letters, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 936)
    - Miscellaneous purchases: printed matter and correspondence, 1947-1954, undated (Box 28, Folder 937)
    - Peace organizations: printed matter, 1951-1953, undated (Box 28, Folder 938-939)
    - Photography: printed matter and routine correspondence, 1947-1956 (Box 28, Folder 940)
    - Political mailings (A-L): form letters and printed matter, 1947-1957 (Box 28, Folder 941)
    - Political mailings (M-Z): form letters and printed matter, 1947-1957 (Box 28, Folder 942)
    - Secretaries: correspondence re employment, 1948-1949, 1951-1956 (Box 28, Folder 943-944)
    - Switzerland: printed matter and routine correspondence, 1947-1956 (Box 28, Folder 945-946)
    - Travel: printed matter and routine correspondence, 1947-1956, undated (Box 29, Folder 947-949)
  - Family
    - Baumann, Otto, [post-1947] (Box 30, Folder 950)
    - Beeson, Jack [son-in-law], 1948-1954, undated (Box 30, Folder 950)
    - Beeson, Nora Sigerist (Mrs. Jack) [daughter], 1947-1949, undated (Box 30, Folder 951)
    - Bickel, André [nephew], 1953, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 951)
    - Bickel, Colette [niece](*), 1952-1955 (Box 30, Folder 952)
    - Bickel, Marcel [nephew](*), 1952-1956 (Box 30, Folder 953)
    - Bickel, Marguerite("Gigite") Sigerist (Mrs. Moritz) [sister](*), 1933-1956, undated (Box 30, Folder 954)
    - Bickel, Moritz [brother-in-law](*), 1948-1955 (Box 30, Folder 955)
    - Burckhardt, Adolf [cousin], 1955 (Box 30, Folder 955)
    - Escher, Charlotte [niece], 1948-1952, undated (Box 30, Folder 956)
    - Escher, Hans, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 956)
    - Escher, Melanie [sister-in-law], 1955 (Box 30, Folder 957)
    - Escher, Peter [nephew], 1947 (Box 30, Folder 957)
    - Escher, Rico [brother-in-law], 1955, undated (Box 30, Folder 958)
    - Escher, Ursula ("Ursel"), 1955 (Box 30, Folder 958)
    - Gonzenbach, Rita ("Serena") von (Mrs. Willi) [cousin], 1951-1956, undated (Box 30, Folder 959)
    - Gonzenbach, Victorine von, 1954-1956, undated (Box 30, Folder 959)
    - Gonzenbach, Willi von [cousin](*), 1952-1955 (Box 30, Folder 960)
    - Lely, Marianne Bickel (Mrs. Jan) [niece](*), 1933, 1939, 1948-1956 (Box 30, Folder 961)
    - Nussio-Escher, Berti, undated (Box 30, Folder 962)
    - Rump, Ariane [cousin], 1953, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 962)
    - Rump, Hedwig Wiskemann (Mrs. Franz) [cousin](*), 1951-1956, undated (Box 30, Folder 963)
    - Sigerist, Carl [cousin], 1956 (Box 30, Folder 964)
    - Sigerist, Emma (Mrs. Ernst H.)[mother](*), 1933, 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 965)
    - Sigerist, Emma (Mrs. Ernst H.): letters of condolence on her death(*), 1954 (Box 30, Folder 966)
    - Sigerist, Emma (Mrs. Ernst H.): letters of condolence on her death(*), 1954 (Box 30, Folder 967)
    - Sigerist, Emmy (Mrs. Henry E.):[wife], 1941, undated (Box 30, Folder 968)
    - Sigerist, Erica [daughter](*), 1941, 1949-1956 (Box 30, Folder 968)
    - Sigerist, Erica: correspondence with persons other than Henry E. Sigerist, 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 969)
    - Sigerist, Fred, 1948-1949 (Box 30, Folder 970)
    - Sigerist, Henry W. [cousin], 1954 (Box 30, Folder 970)
    - Sigerist, (William) Bernard [cousin](*), 1952-1956, undated (Box 30, Folder 971)
    - Wiskemann, Armin [cousin], [1931], 1948-1949, undated (Box 30, Folder 972)
    - Wiskemann, Berthe (Mrs. Bruno) [cousin], 1931, 1934, 1951-1955 (Box 30, Folder 972)
    - Wiskemann, Bruno [cousin], 1939, 1948-1951 (Box 30, Folder 973)
    - Wiskemann, Elsy [cousin], 1954-1956 (Box 30, Folder 973)
    - Wiskemann, Emmy [cousin], 1950 (Box 30, Folder 974)
    - Wiskemann, Franz, 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 974)
    - Wiskemann, Heidy Krayer, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 975)
    - ____, Alex [nephew?], 1951 (Box 30, Folder 975)
  - Nora Sigerist Beeson
    - John F. Fulton(*), 1956-1960 (Box 30, Folder 976)
    - Madeline E. Stanton and others(*), 1960-1970 (Box 30, Folder 977)
  - Collected Letters
    - Letters to Franz Strunz from: (Box 30, Folder 978)
      - Breysig, Kurt, 1913 (Box 30, Folder 978)
      - Günther, [Siegmund?], 1912 (Box 30, Folder 978)
      - Pagel, Julius, 1910 (Box 30, Folder 978)
      - Schweninger, E., 1911 (Box 30, Folder 978)
      - Seeberg, R., 1912 (Box 30, Folder 978)
      - Stadler, H., 1912 (Box 30, Folder 978)
      - [Waldeyer?], ____, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 978)
    - Letters [received by various persons at Johns Hopkins University?] from: (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - Abderhalden, E., 1913 (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - Boas, ____ (Berlin), 1897, 1926 (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - Ewald, ____, 1905 (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - Jaeger, ____ von (Vienna), 1875 (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - Joachim, ____ (Königsberg), 1909 (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - Mathieu, A. (Paris; to John C. Hemmeter), 1909 (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - [Mayeur?], ____ (Paris), 1917 (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - Pagel, Julius (Berlin), 1907 (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - Pavlov, I. P. (Leningrad), 1927 (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - Rosenheim, Th. (Berlin), [1905-1909?] (Box 30, Folder 979)
      - Sudhoff, Karl (Leipzig), 1921-1929 (Box 30, Folder 979)
    - Calling cards addressed to Max Brödel, undated (Box 30, Folder 980)
- Professional Activities, 1920-1957, 1978; Series II; 3 linear feet (7 boxes)
  PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES is arranged in six sections: Board of Economic Warfare, Editing, Lecture Tours, Organizations, Research and Writing, and Universities. Each section is in chronological order, with subsections of correspondence in alphabetical order.
  - Board of Economic Warfare
    - Board of Economic Warfare: "Notification of Efficiency Rating", 1943 June 15 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Fourth United States Civil Service Region, Investigations Division: "Report of Partial Interview and Special Hearing", 1943 November 15 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Foreign Economic Administration: notice of termination of appointment, 1944 May 25 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - United States Civil Service Commission: notice of cancellation of "any and all pending applications and existing eligibilities", 1944 June 3 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Editing
    - Monumenta Medica: notes and prospectuses, [1922-1925] (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Essays on the History of Medicine Presented to Karl Sudhoff…: draft preliminary pages and miscellaneous papers, 1924 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Publications of the Institute for the History of Medicine at the University of Leipzig
      See: box 36, folder 89-93
  - Lecture Tours
    - United States, 1931-1932
      - Announcements and programs, 1931 July-1932 January (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Clippings, 1931 May-1932 March (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1930 December-1931 August-December, 1932 May (Box 31, Folder 6-10)
      - Drafts and notes, undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous papers re: travel, 1931, undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Printed matter re: cruise to Hawaii, 1932 Jan, undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - Schedules, itineraries, biographical data, 1931-1932, undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - South Africa, 1939
      - Correspondence
        - Ad-Al, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 15)
        - An-At, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 16)
        - Ba-Bos, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 17)
        - Bow-Bu, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 18)
        - C, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 19)
        - D, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 20)
        - E, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 21)
        - F, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 22)
        - G, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 23)
        - H, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 24)
        - I-J, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 25)
        - K, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 26)
        - L, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 27)
        - Ma-Milc, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 28)
        - Mill-Mu, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 29)
        - N, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 30)
        - 0, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 31)
        - P-Ri, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 32)
        - Ro-Ru, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 33)
        - Sa-Si, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 34)
        - So-Su, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 35)
        - Th-Tr, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 36)
        - Te, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 37)
        - U-Z, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 38)
      - Lecture schedules, 1939, undated (Box 32, Folder 39)
      - Printed matter, 1939, undated (Box 32, Folder 40)
  - Organizations
    - Printed matter and routine correspondence
      - Switzerland, 1918-1933 (Box 32, Folder 41)
      - Great Britain and Italy, 1921-1925 (Box 32, Folder 42)
      - Germany, 1926-1932 (Box 32, Folder 42)
    - Printed matter, 1932-1940, undated (Box 32, Folder 43-44)
    - Seventh International Congress of Historical Sciences, Warsaw: brochures and miscellaneous papers, 1933 (Box 32, Folder 45)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund, Twelfth Annual Meeting of the Advisory Council and the Boards of Counsel: programs, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 46)
    - Printed matter and routine correspondence
      - Ac-American, 1947-1957 (Box 32, Folder 47)
      - American X,-Comita, 1947-1957 (Box 32, Folder 48)
      - Comite, 1947-1957 (Box 32, Folder 49)
      - Comm-Conv, 1947-1957 (Box 32, Folder 50)
      - D-G, 1947-1957 (Box 32, Folder 51)
      - H, 1947-1957 (Box 33, Folder 52)
      - I-L, 1947-1957 (Box 33, Folder 53)
      - M, 1947-1957 (Box 33, Folder 54)
      - N-Royal C, 1947-1957 (Box 34, Folder 55)
      - Royal Society, 1947-1957 (Box 34, Folder 56)
      - Société I-Z, 1947-1957 (Box 34, Folder 57)
      - Dr. Antoine: A Propos d'un cas d'ulcusduodénal, 1947-1957 (Box 34, Folder 58)
  - Research and Writing
    - Albrecht von Haller: four notebooks containing chronology, "Bibliographie," "Werke," and "Publizierte Briefe", [pre-1923?] (Box 34, Folder 59)